<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Pete Markowsky's blog</title><link href="http://blog.markowsky.us/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.markowsky.us/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.markowsky.us/</id><updated>2019-09-10T15:23:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Sabatical</title><link href="http://blog.markowsky.us/sabatical.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2019-09-10T15:23:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Pete Markowsky</name></author><id>tag:blog.markowsky.us,2019-09-10:sabatical.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the next three months, I'm on a sabatical from
&lt;a href="https://capsule8.com"&gt;Capsule8&lt;/a&gt;. To keep my wits about me and in general to
try and improve my writing and use of time I'm planning on updating this blog
more regularly. With that said I'm hoping to effectively use the time that I'm
not spending with my family doing some projects and reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some project ideas:
  - A Github actions based app to create kubernetes clusters in a gitops style
    workflow
  - A Github actions based journal app
  - A vulnerability scanner for container images similar to &lt;a href="https://github.com/aquasecurity/trivy"&gt;trivy&lt;/a&gt;
  - Learning rust
  - Improving my C++11 skills
  - Relearning terraform
  - Relearning make &amp;amp; cmake
  - Writing lambdas / cloud functions
  - Getting even more familiar with Kubernetes and Other FaaS platforms
  - Getting familiar with kubernetes projects e.g. virtualkubelet, prow
  - &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/?ref=stackshare"&gt;Moving the blog to hugo&lt;/a&gt;
  - A few CTF / Reversing projects to get back in practice
  - Making some open source contributions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some books I'm hoping to read:
  - &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Phoenix-Project-DevOps-Helping-Business/dp/0988262592"&gt;The Phoenix Project&lt;/a&gt;
  - &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Terraform-Running-Writing-Infrastructure-Code-ebook/dp/B06XKHGJHP/ref=sr_1_2?keywords=terraform&amp;amp;qid=1568144201&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sr=8-2"&gt;Terraform Up and Running&lt;/a&gt;
  - &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Modern-CTO-Joel-Beasley/dp/0692076069/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=modern+cto&amp;amp;qid=1568144218&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sr=8-1"&gt;Modern CTO&lt;/a&gt;
  - &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Managers-Path-Leaders-Navigating-Growth/dp/1491973897/ref=pd_sbs_14_2/138-0352009-8539652?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;pd_rd_i=1491973897&amp;amp;pd_rd_r=58f4cad6-435f-43dd-9355-3971f7712c33&amp;amp;pd_rd_w=UqR1I&amp;amp;pd_rd_wg=xgNId&amp;amp;pf_rd_p=d66372fe-68a6-48a3-90ec-41d7f64212be&amp;amp;pf_rd_r=WKRNFP0E4CETDCKT00PR&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=WKRNFP0E4CETDCKT00PR"&gt;The Managers Path&lt;/a&gt;
  - &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Racing-Beam-Computer-Platform-Studies/dp/026201257X/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=racing+the+beam&amp;amp;qid=1568144278&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sr=8-1"&gt;Racing the Beam&lt;/a&gt;
  - &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/C-Programming-Language-4th/dp/0321563840/ref=sr_1_4?keywords=c%2B%2B&amp;amp;qid=1568144412&amp;amp;s=gateway&amp;amp;sr=8-4"&gt;The C++ Programming Language 4th ed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="meta"></category><category term="pelican"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello World!</title><link href="http://blog.markowsky.us/hello-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-03-06T10:58:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Pete Markowsky</name></author><id>tag:blog.markowsky.us,2016-03-06:hello-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After losing my old blog to a Google accounts error leaving it stranded on
blogger, I've been trying to find a decent platform for a while. I've finally
settled on pelican with github pages. So far so good.  Syntax highlighting as
you can see below is pretty straight forward, I can write content in markdown
and the &lt;a href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/3.6.3/index.html"&gt;pelican docs&lt;/a&gt; are
incredibly easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;HELLO WORLD!&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I'm hoping to use the &lt;a href="https://archive.org/web/"&gt;wayback machine&lt;/a&gt; to restore some of my old content over the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="meta"></category><category term="pelican"></category></entry><entry><title>The Jetset Life is Gonna Kill Me</title><link href="http://blog.markowsky.us/the-jetset-life-is-gonna-kill-me.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2006-03-13T08:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Pete Markowsky</name></author><id>tag:blog.markowsky.us,2006-03-13:the-jetset-life-is-gonna-kill-me.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The last two weeks have been a rush of travel and work. It all started when
after a year of saying "I'll come visit you in L.A." to my friend
&lt;a href="http://blog.vort.org"&gt;Russell&lt;/a&gt;, I finally got on a plane and made good on my
promise. Four days of fun in the south California sun and back to work.
Followed by going out midweek, two weeks in a row and a trip to Boston this
past weekend and I'm dead. Was it all worth it? Absolutely! But it's left me
exhausted this morning. Luckily the day seems pretty quiet and I just have to
finish up a few small things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only downside to the travel is that I've not gotten a chance to complete
any of the projects that I'd set out to. The redhat 6.2 oldsploit stuff
remains half undone and the sguil grapher remains half on the drawing board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily this is open source work done in my spare time. In terms of immediate
repercusions no one is really hurt. However because I'm a fool who likes to
publish this stuff, I worry. Why do I worry? Because, I don't want to be
someone who says they'll do something and then doesn't do it. True I get
excited alot but making good on my word is important to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news I'm starting to look for a new job. The one I have is okay, but
not where I ultimately want to end up. So what's next? Where do I want to end
up? I think I'd like to end up in a pentesting role or supporting a pen-testing
team. The idea of having projects that are both creative and interesting as
well as with a specific goal is very appealing to me. Additionally, I like bug
finding in software and reverse engineering. Hopefully I can make my way there
into a field that requires these. If you read my blog and are looking for
someone to do that type of work my resume is posted in the papers section of
this site. Note however that I'm still working on refining the resume as it's
been a little while since I last updated it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="life"></category><category term="work"></category></entry><entry><title>Google Earth To the Rescue</title><link href="http://blog.markowsky.us/google-earth-to-the-rescue.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2006-01-24T21:01:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Pete Markowsky</name></author><id>tag:blog.markowsky.us,2006-01-24:google-earth-to-the-rescue.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, it's 9PM the night before you're going to a conference. You have have no
idea on how to drive to the conference. What do you do? You could try map quest
or google maps. I tried that and wasn't too pleased with the results I got.
Granted they both picked the fastest routes, however since the distance I'm
traveling isn't that great, I'd rather have a simpler route, especially if I'm
going to drive during rush hour. So on a whim I fired up Google Earth and dug
through the various layer files I could turn on. To my amazement I found that
it had the DC Metro. Turns out the metro is much closer to the conference than
I gave it credit for. So now instead of driving during rush hour I'm gonna take
the train. Thanks, Google!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="life"></category></entry></feed>