<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Pete Markowsky's blog</title><link href="http://blog.markowsky.us/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://blog.markowsky.us/feeds/rants.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://blog.markowsky.us/</id><updated>2006-03-13T08:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>The Jetset Life is Gonna Kill Me</title><link href="http://blog.markowsky.us/the-jetset-life-is-gonna-kill-me.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2006-03-13T08:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Pete Markowsky</name></author><id>tag:blog.markowsky.us,2006-03-13:the-jetset-life-is-gonna-kill-me.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The last two weeks have been a rush of travel and work. It all started when
after a year of saying "I'll come visit you in L.A." to my friend
&lt;a href="http://blog.vort.org"&gt;Russell&lt;/a&gt;, I finally got on a plane and made good on my
promise. Four days of fun in the south California sun and back to work.
Followed by going out midweek, two weeks in a row and a trip to Boston this
past weekend and I'm dead. Was it all worth it? Absolutely! But it's left me
exhausted this morning. Luckily the day seems pretty quiet and I just have to
finish up a few small things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only downside to the travel is that I've not gotten a chance to complete
any of the projects that I'd set out to. The redhat 6.2 oldsploit stuff
remains half undone and the sguil grapher remains half on the drawing board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily this is open source work done in my spare time. In terms of immediate
repercusions no one is really hurt. However because I'm a fool who likes to
publish this stuff, I worry. Why do I worry? Because, I don't want to be
someone who says they'll do something and then doesn't do it. True I get
excited alot but making good on my word is important to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news I'm starting to look for a new job. The one I have is okay, but
not where I ultimately want to end up. So what's next? Where do I want to end
up? I think I'd like to end up in a pentesting role or supporting a pen-testing
team. The idea of having projects that are both creative and interesting as
well as with a specific goal is very appealing to me. Additionally, I like bug
finding in software and reverse engineering. Hopefully I can make my way there
into a field that requires these. If you read my blog and are looking for
someone to do that type of work my resume is posted in the papers section of
this site. Note however that I'm still working on refining the resume as it's
been a little while since I last updated it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="life"></category><category term="work"></category></entry></feed>